PROPHETIC MESSAGE FOR 2017 | Prophet T.B. Joshua
Good morning!
(Good morning.)
You may be seated - thank you.
The message is 'Your Faith Will Not Fail'.
Let me take you to the book of Luke 22 from verse 1 to the end but we will go straight to the proof text.
Luke 22:32. Are you there?
"But I have prayed for you, Simon, that your faith may not fail."
And when you have turned back, strengthen your brothers."
Look at the word 'turn back'.
This is the way you are going.
I am going this way and you are saying, "T.B. Joshua, when you have turned back,
remember your brother..."
'When you have turned back, remember your brother and also, help them to turn back.'
Let's read verse 33:
"But he replied, 'Lord, I am ready to go with you to prison and to death'.”
Aah, that is too confident.
The Lord is telling him that, "I'm afraid of you."
"No, don't be afraid of me. I am for You."- "I doubt you will be able to stand for Me."
No, don't doubt I can die for you.
"Jesus answered, 'I tell you, Peter, before the rooster crows today,
you will deny three times that you know me."
Jesus knew that he was going to betray Him.
Jesus said to him again, 'After you have repented, you are to strenghten your brothers'.
It means, Jesus knew that Peter would betray Him and also knew that he would repent.
You are here today - Jesus knows you will repent.
Tell your neighbour.
Because He knows you.
Whatever happens, you are a stakeholder of the Kingdom of God.
You have a seat.
If your seat is empty, He knows that nobody can take over that seat; you will still come back.
Tell your neighbour: "Jesus knows I will repent".
(Jesus knows I will repent.)
If that is the case, as a born-again, your faith may fail but not utterly, not fall off.
Tell your neighbour: "My faith may fail, not utterly." I mean, not fall off.
Again.
(My faith may fail, not utterly.)
Yes. Your faith may fail as a born-again but not utterly - that is, not fall off.
Because that faith is your root, your seed.
It remains in you - that is, you will still come back.
If you are a true born-again, your faith may fail but not utterly.
That means, you will still come back.
If you have wronged now, if you have missed the mark, you will still come back.
(Amen.)
That is the meaning of "born-again".
Once you are born-again, no one and nothing can separate you from God.
It is just to be born-again, genuinely.
But if you are not genuinely born-again - forget.
But, if you are genuinely born-again, nothing and nothing can separate you.
Your faith may fail, not utterly, not fall off.
"Once you are born-again you can not make a mistake" - that is the teaching.
And when you make mistake, aah, you do not want people to know.
Do you know what mistake can lead to?
Mistake cause serious, difficult circumstances.
Mistake cause difficult what?
And through difficult circumstances, you will be offended.
Through situations, you will be offended.
If you have pain now, or a headache, fever or cancer
and that pain is all over you, little things can offend you, overwhelm you.
Even when people greet you - do not greet me!
As if they the ones that had put a cancer in your body.
Through pain, through difficult circumstances, it may be disappointment...
You went to the company, and you expect to receive some goods.
Getting there, they say there is nothing like that.
Or getting to your company, they give you a sack letter.
You realize that in your company the young one has been promoted to supervise you.
As a human being, how would you feel?
Offence.
Whatever you begin to do at that moment will not come from your heart.
Everything around you will irritate and overwhelm you.
You will not want to give your best.
Even if you see money, you want to dupe, embezzle, to change the figures.
Through difficult circumstances, you will be offended.
You wake up in the morning and you find that you have had a nightmare.
Suddenly you look at your bed, you see that you wet the bed, a lot of things happened to you in the dream.
By the time you wake up you feel irritated.
If our faith is being kept up in an hour of temptation, though we may fall -
that is, our faith may fall – yet we shall not be utterly cast down.
In the case of His disciples, Jesus said, 'I pray your faith will not fail'.
Are you with me?
Your faith may fail but not totally, not finally.
As it was with Job, with God's permission, you can be tempted.
You know: satan went to God to beg, "Allow me to do this to this man."
Satan's desire for you, as a Christian, is to have you, to attack you.
Don't forget he begged for permission from God to attack Job.
With God's permission, you can be attacked.
With God's permission, you can be tempted.
So, you Christian, if you now say; "why all this happening to me, why this, why this attack? I am a Christian."
No - with God's permission, you can be tempted.
If God allows it, if God has knowledge of it, if God is aware,
as was the case of Job, don't doubt your God.
Do not begin to doubt; "Why me? Am I not serving the living God? Why God should allow this to happen ?" …
Don’t doubt your God.
Don't let it affect your faith.
You can be attacked but you cannot be destroyed if God allows it.
What is happening to you as a born-again?
You born-again, what is happening to you?
As it was with Job, with God's permission, satan can tempt you.
As it was with Job, with God's permission, satan can attack you but cannot destroy you.
(Amen.)
The SCOAN Saturday Service
Tell your neighbour, "If you are a true born-again, a true follower of Christ,
satan can only attack you if God permits it."
The SCOAN Saturday Service
That means he can only attack you if God permits it.
Such attack will result in your desire for God – will strengthen your desire for God.
It will strengthen your determination for God – will improve your relationship.
Such an attack will make you strong.
Such attack will not impair you but improve you, if God permits it.
It is when you know this, you become a beneficiary.
You see that is it an attack.
Who are you?
I am a child of God.
Yes - God is aware.
God permitted it and He is going to improve me, strengthen my desire, my determination.
I am not here today, to tell you about Moses or Jeremiah but I am telling you about what is happening to you.
(Amen.)
The SCOAN Saturday Service
This is exactly what happens to you.
You would have been growing in your Christian life better than this
but each time this attack came, you forgot you were a Christian.
And if you know you are a Christian, a follower of God, you should know that God has knowledge of it.
And if God has knowledge of it, it means this attack will not impair you but improve you.
If God is aware, this means this temptation will make you stronger.
If God allows it, this means your desire and determination for God will increase.
This is just it.
It's only we cannot continue to pray for an attack or temptation.
It comes naturally, if God allows it.
It's a blessing.
If you are not a Christian, opposite is the case.
We know if you are not a Christian, satan cannot attack his children.
Can satan attack his children?
If satan cannot attack his children…
You are not his children, that is why you are attacked.
Tell your neighbour: "Your faith will not fail".
I cannot hear you.
This coming year, your faith will not fail.
(Amen.)
The SCOAN Saturday Service
Our situation, I mean our difficult circumstances – satan uses them to draw us into sin.
Satan uses our situation, our difficult circumstances, to draw us into what? Into sin.
The moment this attack comes, your thoughts change, you begin to see God in a bad light.
The SCOAN Saturday Service
Oh my God, you begin to see God in a bad light.
Your Saviour will now turn into …
To pray is difficult because your heart is not in its best state.
It is when your heart or your spirit is in its best state that you can pray.
But you are worried.
No one can pray to God while worried.
Tell your neighbour: "No one can pray to God while worried"
You will make an attempt but you are not praying to God, you are praying to yourself.
You are worried.
You now say: Jesus, give me a biscuit...No no no no
Your heart must be at its best because our heart is the prayer room.
Can you see why you keep deceiving yourself?
"Our heart is the prayer room" - tell your neighbour.
Say, "My heart is the prayer room".
So, if your heart is the prayer room, your heart must be at its best.
If your heart is the prayer room, where you keep as the prayer room is an altar…
Look at the altar.
If you came this morning and you saw shit, urine, flies everywhere, dust bins,
would you be able to sit down?
… so, in the same way…
If your heart is not at its best, whom are you praying to?
If you are troubled, you cannot pray and if you pray, you are praying of yourself.
That is why the enemy will often use this as a bait to get you – your situation.
Satan uses our situation, our difficult circumstances -
disappointment, failure, nightmares and everything around you not going well -
satan uses all these to draw us into sin.
He knows it is the only thing that can change your heart.
Your heart when it is at its best – you think about Christ, you meditate, you sing;
but when the trouble comes you change your confession.
You begin to see Jesus in a bad light.
That is why satan was waiting for a time like that to attack Jesus.
After realising Jesus had fasted for forty days and forty nights, satan realized that that man needs food.
And you know that when you fasted for forty days and forty nights then you need food badly.
Oh yes, this is the time to attack this man, situation
This is the time to attack this man, difficult circumstances – oh yes, He has difficulties now.
He needs food.
He now took Him.
He began to seduce Him with food and every beautiful thing in the world.
But thank God – He was not desperate.
But today you are desperate.
Your desperation leads you to take anything.
No matter from where it comes, as long as you have a relief.
Jesus was not desperate.
He said, 'Although I am hungry, but I am not desperate'.
Although I am hungry, I've been fasting for forty days and forty nights, I am looking for something to eat
but I am not desperate.
To be desperate is to be so anxious…
You do not mind from where the food comes from, you just want to eat.
It was a food, and you tested, and it was good.
As Jesus gives food, satan too, has his own food.
His food lasts for now but God's food lasts for eternity.
This is why you can't receive blessing - as you receive it, it disappears.
You become a billionaire today, next year you become a poor man.
The peace I give, the money I give, and the food I am giving you ...
Not as the world gives you, not as satan gives them.
Satan will give you all this, looking like things I give you, but the difference is
at the time you need it most it disappears.
You see many in our times.
Some of the blessings you need now - at the time you need those blessing most - you cannot find them.
In summary: as it was with Job, with God's permission, you can be tempted.
As it was with Job, with God's permission, you can be attacked by satan.
If you look around and see; yes – I am follower of God, nothing is wrong.
An attack comes - you should know that God is aware.
God has knowledge of it
God allows it.
Let them come - promotion is about to come.
If God aware of what you are going through, what is happening to you,
yes, the question is – what does He want to prove?
Ask yourself, "What does He want to prove?"
Speak to yourself and speak out.
When you pray: Lord Jesus, I have a headache – heal me, and you are not healed.
You say you do not have faith.
You shouldn’t base your faith on the healing of your sickness.
You may not be healed, yet you have faith.
These are the challenges we are facing now.
We always base our faith on improvement of our prayer.
We base our faith on what?
Improvement of what?
A prayer.
If you pray and pray and your prayer is answered – you agree that you have faith.
If you pray and pray and your prayer is not answered – you do not have faith.
It honours God when we believe in Him when every sense contradicts Him.
When everything is not good and you still believe in Him, it honours Him more
than when everything is good and you believe in Him.
The SCOAN Saturday Service
Are you with me?
It honours God most when you believe in Him when everything looks bad
than believing in Him when things look good.
You are in church today because everything seems to look bad,
but the moment things turn around, and you begin to count in thousands, trillion, houses, and other;
you will check your expensive watch,
you look at the time and say: no no Joshua, I can't sit here - it is too warm, too hot here.
But here it is not hot now.
You are ready to sit down.
The SCOAN Saturday Service
Now, you are here today and I believe next time you will come as an ex-loser.
Ex-loser.
You need to believe God.
The same way, if not more - the way you believe in Him now.
The SCOAN Saturday Service
And also, always realize that your difficult situations and circumstances are the things satan uses
to drive you into sin.
You know, sin begins in our heart.
The war you are seeing today started from the heart.
The discussion: "we are going to do that…" before planning.
Therefore, the wrong or whatever you might have done started from your heart.
When satan uses our situation, our difficult circumstances to drag us into sin.
it means at that moment you are attacked -
whether it is a nightmare - when you wake up...
It is always difficult for you to pray.
When you wake up and you find that this is bad, this is a nightmare...
Even when you pray, you pray with a disturbed heart.
When you pray with a disturbed heart, you are not praying to God but to yourself.
That is an attack.
He uses those attacks to drag us into sin, to separate us from God,
to overthrow us from our position as a child of God.
Any time there is an attack,
if anyone tells you that because you are a Christian, you will not be attacked,
what of if God permits it, allows it, has knowledge of it or is aware?
So also, faith is your root to God.
There is nothing you can do with a root, unless you do not have that root at all.
It is your seed; it remains in you.
No matter how it fails, but not finally or totally.
May God bless His word.
Thank you.
How does this message apply to you?
Can somebody stand up to tell me?
I am a Christian for now.
Thank you.
Clap for him.
He says he is a Christian.
Not only a Christian, but a born-again Christian.
- If I'm right...?
- You are right.
You can answer the question.
This message is an inspiration.
But as a Christian, before now - how did you handle the issue of faith?
You say you are a born-again.
What was your understanding of issue of faith?
Tell us how it was before now.
Before now - when I get something and get hurt, I get discouraged.
So with this message - it gives an inspiration that any temptation in life is a test, to prove my trust in God.
So, it permits to believe more in God.
There is a question you need to ask yourself:
when there is an attack or whatever you are facing, you need to ask yourself,
"Are you still a born again"?
If you can answer that question yourself: "I am a born-again" - good.
There is another question: "What does God want to prove?"
God wants to prove Himself as faithful, when I am facing temptation.
If I were to encourage myself with this message today,
which is an inspiration: when I face temptation, I know that God wants to improve my life
through that trial to become a testimony in my life.
Thank you.
Never forget that it honours Him more to believe God when we are facing challenges.
Tell your neighbour.
It honours God more to believe in Him when we are facing difficult circumstances.
You want to improve your relationship with God.
That is the time to improve it.
Oh my God.
The SCOAN Saturday Service
Every true Christian would like to improve their relationship with God.
No matter the level of your relationship with God, you want improvement.
You want to sleep and see visions, understand His voice, hear His voice in your heart,
God to talk to you and you to God, feel Him, reach that level, see visions,
you want to know God's opinion about yourself and about others.
Yet, although you are a true Christian you cannot tell people the opinion of God about others.
You do not even know the God's opinion about yourself.
What kind of Christian are you?
Thank you brother.
We are going to ask a different question entirely.
First of all tell us your position before God.
What do you understand about an attack now, if you are a Christian, Sir?
As a journalist I have a different opinion about what attack is all about.
I believe that an attack differs from one country to another.
The way you get attacked in the western world is different from the way you got attacked in Africa.
So I see attacks in Africa as more spiritual.
But the other world is just by the grace of God.
But I have a contrary opinion to what man of God has said before I got here.
As a journalist I was looking for news to write
But when you said something about Peter Simon - if Peter Simon who failed, who am I?
I am a mere mortal.
I can fail at any time.
OK, what my brother asked - I want somebody to answer this question.
What type of attacks or temptations are we talking about?
Any foolish thing that the devil can use against us.
Be it sickness, or children turning against you.
I want to thank you - thank you.
What do you understand about this so-called attack?
To me as a Christian and a born-again,
I believe that an attack is anything that would want me to react, or to diminish my faith in Christ.
And the way we react, or we want to defend ourselves during the attack really matters.
So, as a child of God when any attack comes we have to think, and we know that any attack -
it is a way God uses to have us much more faith in Him.
The SCOAN Saturday Service
What I learned through this message are two characteristics, of a true "born-again".
Number one is that we know a true "born-again" - when he misses the mark,
because naturally he comes back to repentance.
And second characteristics is that a true "born-again" can be attacked only when God permits it.
This is to improve his faith and make him come closer in his relationship with God.
And this will help him.
Thank you.
You listen what he said: there are two things that he said here.
When a truly born-again Christian is attacked, he will surely come back to repentance.
That is a true born-again.
It comes naturally.
That you are a born-again does not mean you cannot be attacked
but the difference between you and those who are not born again is that when you are attacked,
you will come to repentance.
That is born-again.
Those who are not born-again when they attack them, they attack back
and continue to live that life of attack.
The attack they receive will make them to go deeper in the dark.
From one witch doctor to another…
They begin to point an "accuse finger", looking for his attacker.
A time of attack is a time of promotion, to improve your relationship with God.
Take note – when you are born-again, nothing can separate you from the love of God.
What is the love of God?
The love of God is the way of God.
The love of God is eternal life.
It is all about being a born-again.
You just need to check yourself if you are really a born-again.
How do we know we are born again?
Sit down Sir.
Can somebody tell me how do you know you are a born-again?
How do you know you are born-again?
Uzbekistan - speaker.
She says she is from Uzbekistan, and when she was coming here she was attacked
and her bank card was blocked, but she went into prayer and said,
"Lord this is your will, and if you want me to be there I will be there".
So, she received it, she humbled herself and the Lord opened a way for her to come here.
Anything close to Jesus receives attack.
It is not only while coming here.
Even if you apply for a job and that job would benefit you,
and your life depends on that job, and it is a destine job.
Immediately you think about applying the attack starts.
The SCOAN Saturday Service